{
  "688587": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper English equivalent of the word “втома”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360035",
      "answerText": "fatigue"
    }
  },
  "688588": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper English equivalent of the word “шум у серці”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360039",
      "answerText": "murmur"
    }
  },
  "688589": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper English equivalent of the word “рубцювання”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360046",
      "answerText": "scarring"
    }
  },
  "688590": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper English equivalent of the word “прояв (захворювання)”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360050",
      "answerText": "manifestation"
    }
  },
  "688591": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper English equivalent of the word “оніміння”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360058",
      "answerText": "numbing"
    }
  },
  "688592": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper English equivalent of the word “засіб від кашлю”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360060",
      "answerText": "antitussive"
    }
  },
  "688593": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper English equivalent of the word “подагра”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360064",
      "answerText": "gout"
    }
  },
  "688594": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper English equivalent of the word “не їсти, постити”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360072",
      "answerText": "to fast"
    }
  },
  "688595": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper English equivalent of the word “шприц”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360074",
      "answerText": "syringe"
    }
  },
  "688596": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper English equivalent of the word “закреп”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360083",
      "answerText": "constipation"
    }
  },
  "688597": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper English equivalent of the word “слиновиділення”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360084",
      "answerText": "salivation"
    }
  },
  "688598": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper English equivalent of the word “вщухати”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360090",
      "answerText": "to subside"
    }
  },
  "688599": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper English equivalent of the word “селезінка”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360096",
      "answerText": "spleen"
    }
  },
  "688600": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper English equivalent of the word “спазмування, судома”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360099",
      "answerText": "cramping"
    }
  },
  "688601": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper English equivalent of the word “рідкісний”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360108",
      "answerText": "rare"
    }
  },
  "688602": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper missing word or word combination in the sentence “The most prevalent cause of heart diseases is high blood pressure, also called ...”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360109",
      "answerText": "hypertension"
    }
  },
  "688603": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper missing word or word combination in the sentence “… drugs are administered by placing the medication under the tongue”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360115",
      "answerText": "sublingual"
    }
  },
  "688604": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper missing word or word combination in the sentence “Peripheral arterial disease is a disorder in which … builds up in the arteries”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360119",
      "answerText": "plaque"
    }
  },
  "688605": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper missing word or word combination in the sentence “Emphysema is a chronic lung disease in which the … at the end of the small bronchioles are enlarged or over-inflated and are eventually destroyed”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360125",
      "answerText": "alveoli"
    }
  },
  "688606": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper missing word or word combination in the sentence “In the lungs the blood picks up … and returns to the left side of the heart”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360129",
      "answerText": "oxygen"
    }
  },
  "688607": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper missing word or word combination in the sentence “Maintaining a healthy body weight helps … heart attacks”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360135",
      "answerText": "to prevent"
    }
  },
  "688608": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper missing word or word combination in the sentence “ … is the inflammation of the lungs caused by bacteria, viruses and allergy”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360141",
      "answerText": "pneumonia"
    }
  },
  "688609": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper missing word or word combination in the sentence “In order to check the patient’s lungs capacity, doctor performs …”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360146",
      "answerText": "spirometry"
    }
  },
  "688610": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper missing word or word combination in the sentence “The patient’s cough is … as it doesn’t produce sputum”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360149",
      "answerText": "dry"
    }
  },
  "688611": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper missing word or word combination in the sentence “Type 2 diabetes is caused by a lack of …”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360156",
      "answerText": "insulin"
    }
  },
  "688612": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper missing word or word combination in the sentence “Probiotics are live … that help to prevent and treat some illnesses”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360160",
      "answerText": "bacteria"
    }
  },
  "688613": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper definition of the term “pathogens”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360164",
      "answerText": "are harmful organisms and viruses that can cause disease"
    }
  },
  "688614": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper definition of the term “heartburn”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360172",
      "answerText": "is a condition in which stomach acids go back up into the esophagus, causing chest pain and burning sensation"
    }
  },
  "688615": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper definition of the term “feces”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360175",
      "answerText": "are waste products of digestion formed in the large intestine"
    }
  },
  "688616": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper definition of the term “polyphagia”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360179",
      "answerText": "is an excessive eating in diabetes, the inability to use glucose properly can cause a sense of hunger"
    }
  },
  "688617": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper definition of the term “gestational diabetes”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360185",
      "answerText": "is the condition when the blood glucose level of the mother goes too high during pregnancy"
    }
  },
  "688618": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper definition of the term “whooping cough”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360189",
      "answerText": "is an infection of the respiratory tract caused by Bordetella Pertussis bacteria"
    }
  },
  "688619": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper definition of the term “anticoagulant”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360196",
      "answerText": "a medication that keeps blood from clotting"
    }
  },
  "688620": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper definition of the term “dyspnea”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360199",
      "answerText": "is shortness of breath"
    }
  },
  "688621": {
    "questionText": "Choose the proper definition of the term “cardiac arrest”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360207",
      "answerText": "sudden loss of heart function"
    }
  },
  "688622": {
    "questionText": "Choose the correct form of the missing verb “Look! The doctor … instruments for examination”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360209",
      "answerText": "is preparing"
    }
  },
  "688623": {
    "questionText": "Choose the correct form of the missing verb “She … operations on the lungs at 2 p.m. yesterday”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360217",
      "answerText": "was watching"
    }
  },
  "688624": {
    "questionText": "Choose the correct form of the missing verb “This man … HIV during transfusion of blood components from a sick donor ten years ago”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360219",
      "answerText": "contracted"
    }
  },
  "688625": {
    "questionText": "Choose the correct form of the missing verb “Students … all possible oral manifestations of AIDS by the end of their class yesterday”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360227",
      "answerText": "had discussed"
    }
  },
  "688626": {
    "questionText": "Choose the correct form of the missing verb “I … an interesting documentary about transfer of HIV from monkeys to people at 6 o’clock yesterday”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360230",
      "answerText": "was watching"
    }
  },
  "688627": {
    "questionText": "Choose the correct form of the missing verb “The child … a gastroenterologist a week ago”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360234",
      "answerText": "visited"
    }
  },
  "688628": {
    "questionText": "Choose the correct form of the missing verb “Jane … a nurse before she became a GP”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360242",
      "answerText": "had been"
    }
  },
  "688629": {
    "questionText": "Choose the correct form of the missing verb “They usually … such problems at the conferences”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360244",
      "answerText": "discuss"
    }
  },
  "688630": {
    "questionText": "Choose the correct form of the missing verb “In his lecture the professor already … the difference between indigestion and food intolerance”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360252",
      "answerText": "has explained"
    }
  },
  "688631": {
    "questionText": "Choose the correct form of the missing verb “She … treating her joints this week”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360255",
      "answerText": "has started"
    }
  },
  "688632": {
    "questionText": "Choose the correct form of the missing verb “They … their laboratory tests two days ago”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360260",
      "answerText": "got"
    }
  },
  "688633": {
    "questionText": "Use the correct preposition “The doctor often examines the mouth … sores, inflamed gums, sore tongue”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360264",
      "answerText": "for"
    }
  },
  "688634": {
    "questionText": "Use the correct preposition “Roger has worked as a dentist ... twelve years”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360270",
      "answerText": "for"
    }
  },
  "688635": {
    "questionText": "Use the correct preposition “Sandra has studied in our class ... October”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360276",
      "answerText": "since"
    }
  },
  "688636": {
    "questionText": "Use the correct preposition “It is an inappropriate antibody reaction … normal proteins found on beta cells”:",
    "categoryId": "10969",
    "answer": {
      "answerId": "3360281",
      "answerText": "to"
    }
  }
}